<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Platforms on Tech radar</title>
    <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Platforms on Tech radar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/android/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/android/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Android is a mobile operating system based on a modified version of the Linux kernel and other open source software, designed primarily for touchscreen mobile devices such as smartphones and tablets.
Why ? For who ?  Beagle Framework  Resources  homepage Documentation  Resources (Portuguese) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/bucket-s3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/bucket-s3/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? An Amazon S3 bucket is a public cloud storage resource available in Amazon Web Services&#39; (AWS) Simple Storage Service (S3), an object storage offering. Amazon S3 buckets, which are similar to file folders, store objects, which consist of data and its descriptive metadata.
Why ? Store data in Amazon S3 and secure it from unauthorized access with encryption features and access management tools. S3 is the only object storage service that allows you to block public access to all of objects at the bucket or the account level with S3 Block Public Access.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/docker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/docker/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Docker is a set of platform as a service products that use OS-level virtualization to deliver software in packages called containers. Containers are isolated from one another and bundle their own software, libraries and configuration files; they can communicate with each other through well-defined channels.
Why ? The Docker goal is to ease the creation, deploy and the delivery of an application using the so called Containers.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/elasticsearch/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/elasticsearch/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Elasticsearch is a search engine based on the Lucene library. It provides a distributed, multitenant-capable full-text search engine with an HTTP web interface and schema-free JSON documents.
Why ? For who ? Resources  homepage The SSPL is Not an Open Source License  Resources (Portuguese) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/envoy/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/envoy/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Envoy Proxy is a modern, high performance, small footprint edge and service proxy. Envoy is most comparable to software load balancers such as NGINX and HAProxy. Originally written and deployed at Lyft, Envoy now has a vibrant contributor base and is an official Cloud Native Computing Foundation project.
Why ? As on the ground microservice practitioners quickly realize, the majority of operational problems that arise when moving to a distributed architecture are ultimately grounded in two areas: networking and observability.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/github/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/github/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? GitHub, Inc. is a provider of Internet hosting for software development and version control using Git. It offers the distributed version control and source code management functionality of Git, plus its own features.
Why ? GitHub is a website for developers and programmers to collaboratively work on code. The primary benefit of GitHub is its version control system, which allows for seamless collaboration without compromising the integrity of the original project.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/ingress/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/ingress/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Ingress exposes HTTP and HTTPS routes from outside the cluster to services within the cluster. Traffic routing is controlled by rules defined on the Ingress resource.
Why ? For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage  Resources (Portuguese) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/ios/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/ios/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? iOS (formerly iPhone OS) is a mobile operating system created and developed by Apple Inc. exclusively for its hardware. It is the operating system that powers many of the company&amp;rsquo;s mobile devices, including the iPhone and iPod Touch; the term also included the versions running on iPads until the name iPadOS was introduced with version 13 in 2019. It is the world&amp;rsquo;s second-most widely installed mobile operating system, after Android.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/istio/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/istio/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Istio extends Kubernetes to establish a programmable, application-aware network using the powerful Envoy service proxy. Working with both Kubernetes and traditional workloads, Istio brings standard, universal traffic management, telemetry, and security to complex deployments.
Why ? Istio lets you connect, secure, control, and observe services. At a high level, Istio helps reduce the complexity of these deployments, and eases the strain on your development teams. It is a completely open source service mesh that layers transparently onto existing distributed applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/keycloak/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/keycloak/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Keycloak is an open source software product to allow single sign-on with Identity and Access Management aimed at modern applications and services. As of March 2018 this WildFly community project is under the stewardship of Red Hat who use it as the upstream project for their RH-SSO product.
Why ? Keycloak offers everything a sophisticated user management tool needs – without having to log on repeatedly with every login and into every system-as well as system security, social logins, support for mobile apps and integration into other solutions.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/kubernetes/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/kubernetes/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Kubernetes is an open-source container-orchestration system for automating computer application deployment, scaling, and management. It was originally designed by Google and is now maintained by the Cloud Native Computing Foundation.
Why ? Kubernetes is an open-source system to automate the deployment, scaling, and management of containerized applications. This container management system&amp;rsquo;s popularity soared with the rise of businesses operating on cloud infrastructure and technology
For who ?</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/mongodb/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/mongodb/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? MongoDB is a source-available cross-platform document-oriented database program. Classified as a NoSQL database program, MongoDB uses JSON-like documents with optional schemas. MongoDB is developed by MongoDB Inc. and licensed under the Server Side Public License.
Why ? For who ? Resources  homepage The SSPL is Not an Open Source License  Resources (Portuguese) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/nodejs/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/nodejs/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Node.js is an open-source, cross-platform, back-end JavaScript runtime environment that runs on the V8 engine and executes JavaScript code outside a web browser.
Why ? Node.js is primarily used for non-blocking, event-driven servers, due to its single-threaded nature. It&amp;rsquo;s used for traditional web sites and back-end API services, but was designed with real-time, push-based architectures in mind.
For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage Documentation Source code  Resources (Portuguese) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/postgresql/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/postgresql/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? PostgreSQL, also known as Postgres, is a free and open-source relational database management system emphasizing extensibility and SQL compliance. It was originally named POSTGRES, referring to its origins as a successor to the Ingres database developed at the University of California, Berkeley.
Why ? It is an advanced open-source object-relational system which applies SQL language. Postgres allows you to store large and sophisticated data safely. It helps developers to build the most complex applications, run administrative tasks and create integral environments.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/prometheus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/prometheus/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Prometheus is a free software application used for event monitoring and alerting. It records real-time metrics in a time series database built using a HTTP pull model, with flexible queries and real-time alerting.
Why ? For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage Documentation Source code  Resources (Portuguese) </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/rabbitmq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/rabbitmq/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? RabbitMQ is an open-source message-broker software that originally implemented the Advanced Message Queuing Protocol and has since been extended with a plug-in architecture to support Streaming Text Oriented Messaging Protocol, MQ Telemetry Transport, and other protocols.
Why ? RabbitMQ is therefore ideal for long-running tasks or blocking tasks, allowing web servers to respond quickly to requests instead of being forced to perform computationally intensive tasks on the spot.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/redis/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/redis/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Redis is an in-memory data structure store, used as a distributed, in-memory key–value database, cache and message broker, with optional durability. Redis supports different kinds of abstract data structures, such as strings, lists, maps, sets, sorted sets, HyperLogLogs, bitmaps, streams, and spatial indices.
Why ? Redis simplifies your code by enabling you to write fewer lines of code to store, access, and use data in your applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/swagger/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/swagger/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Swagger is an Interface Description Language for describing RESTful APIs expressed using JSON. Swagger is used together with a set of open-source software tools to design, build, document, and use RESTful web services. Swagger includes automated documentation, code generation, and test-case generation.
Why ? Swagger is a set of rules (in other words, a specification) for a format describing REST APIs. The format is both machine-readable and human-readable.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/vcluster/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/platforms/vcluster/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Virtual clusters have their own API server which makes them much more powerful and better isolated than namespaces, but they are also much cheaper than creating separate &amp;ldquo;real&amp;rdquo; Kubernetes clusters.
Why ? Virtual clusters solve many of the problems that namespaces present, such as:
 Cluster-Scoped Resources: Certain resources live globally in the cluster, and you can’t isolate them using namespaces. For example, installing istio or any other operator in different versions is not possible within a single cluster.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
