<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Tools on Tech radar</title>
    <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Tools on Tech radar</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/casbin/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/casbin/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Casbin is a powerful and efficient open-source access control library. It provides support for enforcing authorization based on various access control models like ACL, RBAC, ABAC for Golang, Java, Node.js, PHP, Python, .NET (C#), Delphi and Rust.
Why ? An authorization library that supports access control models like ACL, RBAC, ABAC for Golang, Java, C/C++, Node.js, Javascript, PHP, Laravel, Python, .NET (C#), Delphi, Rust, Ruby, Swift (Objective-C), Lua (OpenResty), Dart (Flutter) and Elixir</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/chai/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/chai/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Chai is a BDD / TDD assertion library for node and the browser that can be delightfully paired with any javascript testing framework.
Why ? Chai has several interfaces that allow the developer to choose the most comfortable. The chain-capable BDD styles provide an expressive language &amp;amp; readable style, while the TDD assert style provides a more classical feel.
For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage Docs  Resources (Portuguese)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/codecov/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/codecov/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Code coverage is a measurement used to express which lines of code were executed by a test suite. We use three primary terms to describe each line executed.
Why ? Code coverage tools incentivize developers to write tests and increase coverage. During the process of writing tests, the developer may discover new bugs or syntax issues in the source code that are important to resolve before distributing the application.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/dependabot/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/dependabot/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Dependabot creates pull requests to keep your dependencies secure and up-to-date.
Why ? For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage  Resources (Portuguese)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/git/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/git/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Git is software for tracking changes in any set of files, usually used for coordinating work among programmers collaboratively developing source code during software development. Its goals include speed, data integrity, and support for distributed, non-linear workflows.
Why ? Git is the most commonly used version control system. Git tracks the changes you make to files, so you have a record of what has been done, and you can revert to specific versions should you ever need to.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/gitguardian/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/gitguardian/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? GitGuardian Internal Repositories Monitoring focuses on repositories owned by your company, both public and private. These are the repositories that you know exist, where you have full authority to enforce your security policies (as opposed to your developers&#39; personal repositories for example).
Why ? For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage  Resources (Portuguese)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/github-action/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/github-action/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? GitHub Actions makes it easy to automate all your software workflows, now with world-class CI/CD. Build, test, and deploy your code right from GitHub. Make code reviews, branch management, and issue triaging work the way you want.
Why ? For who ?  CharlesCD Horusec  Resources  homepage  Resources (Portuguese)  Github Actions: uma introdução  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/github-app-dco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/github-app-dco/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? This App enforces the Developer Certificate of Origin (DCO) on Pull Requests. It requires all commit messages to contain the Signed-off-by line with an email address that matches the commit author.
Why ? Make sure that any contributions as commits are open source.
For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  homepage  Resources (Portuguese)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/graalvm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/graalvm/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? GraalVM is a Java VM and JDK based on HotSpot/OpenJDK, implemented in Java. It supports additional programming languages and execution modes, like ahead-of-time compilation of Java applications for fast startup and low memory footprint.
Why ? GraalVM. GraalVM is a high-performance runtime that provides significant improvements in application performance and efficiency which is ideal for microservices. It is designed for applications written in Java, JavaScript, LLVM-based languages such as C and C++, and other dynamic languages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/helm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/helm/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Helm is the K8s equivalent of yum or apt. Helm deploys charts, which you can think of as a packaged application. It is a collection of all your versioned, pre-configured application resources which can be deployed as one unit. You can then deploy another version of the chart with a different set of configuration.
Why ? Helm is a tool that streamlines installing and managing Kubernetes applications.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/hugo/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Hugo is one of the most popular open-source static site generators. With its amazing speed and flexibility, Hugo makes building websites fun again.
Why ? Hugo is for people who want to hand code their own website without worrying about setting up complicated runtimes, dependencies and databases. Hugo is for people building a blog, a company site, a portfolio site, documentation, a single landing page, or a website with thousands of pages.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/intellij/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/intellij/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? IntelliJ IDEA is an integrated development environment written in Java for developing computer software. It is developed by JetBrains, and is available as an Apache 2 Licensed community edition, and in a proprietary commercial edition. Both can be used for commercial development.
Why ? IntelliJ IDEA analyzes your code, looking for connections between symbols across all project files and languages. Using this information it provides indepth coding assistance, quick navigation, clever error analysis, and, of course, refactorings.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/kubectl/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/kubectl/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? The Kubernetes command-line tool, kubectl, allows you to run commands against Kubernetes clusters. You can use kubectl to deploy applications, inspect and manage cluster resources, and view logs. For more information including a complete list of kubectl operations, see the kubectl reference documentation.
Why ? Kubectl is your cockpit to control Kubernetes. It allows you to perform every possible Kubernetes operation. From a technical point of view, kubectl is a client for the Kubernetes API.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/maven/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/maven/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Apache Maven is a software project management and comprehension tool. Based on the concept of a project object model (POM), Maven can manage a project&amp;rsquo;s build, reporting and documentation from a central piece of information.
If you think that Maven could help your project, you can find out more information in the &amp;ldquo;About Maven&amp;rdquo; section of the navigation. This includes an in-depth description of what Maven is and a list of some of its main features.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/npm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/npm/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Npm is a package manager for the JavaScript programming language maintained by npm, Inc. npm is the default package manager for the JavaScript runtime environment Node.js. It consists of a command line client, also called npm, and an online database of public and paid-for private packages, called the npm registry.
Why ? Npm install downloads a package and it&amp;rsquo;s dependencies. &amp;hellip; When run without arguments, npm install downloads dependencies defined in a package.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/supertest/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/supertest/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? The motivation with this module is to provide a high-level abstraction for testing HTTP, while still allowing you to drop down to the lower-level API provided by superagent.
Why ? For who ?  CharlesCD  Resources  Source  Resources (Portuguese)    </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/vscode/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/vscode/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Visual Studio Code is a source-code editor made by Microsoft for Windows, Linux and macOS. Features include support for debugging, syntax highlighting, intelligent code completion, snippets, code refactoring, and embedded Git.
Why ? Visual Studio Code combines the simplicity of a source code editor with powerful developer tooling, like IntelliSense code completion and debugging. &amp;hellip; The delightfully frictionless edit-build-debug cycle means less time fiddling with your environment, and more time executing on your ideas.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title></title>
      <link>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/yarn/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://zupit.github.io/opensource-tech-radar/tools/yarn/</guid>
      <description>What is it ? Yarn is a package manager that doubles down as project manager. Whether you work on one-shot projects or large monorepos, as a hobbyist or an enterprise user, we&amp;rsquo;ve got you covered.
Why ? Yarn is a package manager for your code. It allows you to use and share (e.g. JavaScript) code with other developers from around the world. Yarn does this quickly, securely, and reliably so you don&amp;rsquo;t ever have to worry.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
